Guide to the Robert Steck Papers ALBA.104
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Robert Steck Papers
1917-1998
1936-1993
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Steck, Robert
ALBA.104
7.25 Linear Feet in 7 record cartons and 2 oversize folders
In January 1937, Robert Steck, actor and social activist, sailed to Europe to volunteer for the Abraham Lincoln Brigade in the Spanish Civil War. He was taken prisoner in April 1938 and held for seventeen months. After serving in World War II, Steck became a history teacher. Throughout his career, Steck also organized many events designed to present the history of the Spanish Civil War. The collection reflects the range of Steck's progressive activities and concerns, including his long association with the communal adult camp, Camp Unity, correspondence with members of the Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade, and biographical profiles and research associated with his collaboration on Carl Geiser's book Prisoners of the Good Fight.
Provenance
The bulk of material regarding Camp Unity, Camp Calumet, and Sophie Saroff was donated to Tamiment Library by Robert Steck in 1979. The remaining Robert Steck Papers were donated to the Abraham Lincoln Brigade Archives by Robert Steck between 1979 and 1998. This portion of the collection came to New York University in January 2001 as part of the original acquisition of ALBA collections, formerly housed at Brandeis University.
Access Restrictions
Materials are open to researchers. Please contact the Tamiment Library & Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives for more information and to schedule an appointment, tamiment.wagner@nyu.edu or 212-998-2630.
Historical/Biographical Note
Robert Steck was born in 1912 in Rock Island, Illinois. One of five brothers, he inherited a keen awareness of society's injustices from his father, a fruit and vegetable wholesaler and member of the Freethinking Society, leading Steck to a lifelong commitment to public service and political activism. While attending St. Ambrose College in Iowa, Steck discovered the theater and, after a stint as a truck driver for his father's business, landed in New York City, where he worked on the staff of New Theater Magazine alongside editor Herb Kline (who would later fight with Steck in the Spanish Civil War). Here Steck wed his theater skills to social activism, joining Studio One's Theater of Action, an offshoot of the WPA-sponsored Workers Laboratory Theater. In the summer, Steck worked at Camp Unity, an interracial, socialist adult camp, first as an actor, then as director of activities.
By January 1937, Steck's Camp Unity associates Yale Stuart and Philip Bard had departed for Spain to fight in the Spanish Civil War (SCW). Steck, already active in efforts for the Republican cause, soon followed. He sailed on the Ile de France in February 1937, where he joined the first group of U.S. International Brigades volunteers required to walk from France over the Pyrenees to get into Spain (their passports had been stamped "not valid for travel in Spain"). In the following months, Steck served in the International Brigades with the First Regiment de Tren, where he was elected political commissar; worked with British writer Ralph Bates, putting out the magazine Volunteer for Liberty; headed the Tarazona Base Cultural Commission, adapting his theater experience to the political and social realities of the war and creating skits performed off the back of trucks (known as "Buffoons on Trucks"); and was rifleman, runner and battalion scout for the Third Lincoln company.
On April 9, 1938, during the retreat from Gandesa, Steck was captured by Italian fascists, who would have executed him were it not for Mussolini's order to exchange International Brigaders for captured fascists. Steck was first kept for two days in complete darkness at the bottom of a cistern, then transferred to the prison at San Pedro de Cardena, where he spent the following seventeen months. While in prison Steck organized an "Institute for Higher Learning" and, together with fellow-prisoners Hy Wallach and Sidney Rosenblatt, put out a handwritten newspaper, "Jaily News," illustrated by British prisoner Jimmy Moon. They made only a single copy of each issue, concealing it beneath the floorboards when it wasn't being surreptitiously circulated among the prisoners (Steck later smuggled two issues home under his clothes). Meanwhile, Steck's father joined the Friends of the Prisoners committee in the U.S. to work for his son's release. It was only after the war had ended that the State Department finally negotiated the release of a group of eleven prisoners that included Steck.
Back in the States, Steck married Josephine (Jo) Savage. He also quickly connected with the recently-formed Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade (VALB), chairing the Committee for the Release of the International Prisoners in Spain. Steck returned to Camp Unity as director of activities in the summer of 1940, finding a welcome refuge for himself and other veterans, and in the autumn and winter continued his social work at community centers in the Bronx and Philadelphia. He worked as well for a short time as a welder at Todd Shipyards. Steck joined the U.S. Army in 1943, serving until 1946 in the Medical Corps at Fort Meade, in the Specialized Training Program at Georgetown University, and in Intelligence training (in Russian) at Camp Ritchie. His deployment overseas was repeatedly put off, however, and Steck became convinced that this was due to discrimination based upon his participation in the SCW.
After an honorable discharge, Steck again returned to Camp Unity as director of activities. He left in 1952 as a result of differences over policy. In 1956, after running a travel agency for a year, Steck formed a communally-oriented children's camp, Camp Calumet, with friend and Camp Unity associate, Sophie Saroff. In 1967, Steck became a full time fifth grade teacher at P.S. 40 in the South Bronx, then taught high school history and social studies in New Jersey, New York and later in Connecticut, where he and Jo settled in Lime Rock. He retired from teaching in 1978, affording him more time to devote his energies to a broad spectrum of social issues, including nuclear disarmament, the Nicaraguan revolution, the struggle in El Salvador, and justice for Palestinians. For years, he spent every Saturday standing in a Vigil for Peace on the Salisbury Green in Connecticut.
Steck remained a core member of VALB, serving twice on the Executive Board of the National Council, and chairing the Prisoner Historical Committee. From 1979 through 1986, he worked closely with veteran Carl Geiser on Geiser's Prisoners of the Good Fight, organizing numerous fundraising endeavors, conducting extensive research, and traveling internationally to locate American ex-prisoners. From his research and interviews, Steck wrote 120 biographical profiles that underlay Geiser's account of the Americans' experience in Spanish prisons. During this period Steck also used his research to write and publish a pamphlet on Walter Fairbanks Grant, a prisoner killed in Spain; and an article for Jewish Currents about Sol Leiserowitz, another prisoner who disappeared. Prisoners of the Good Fight was published in 1986.
Scope and Content Note
Series I, General Files, 1937-1998 (bulk 1975-1996).
This series, comprised of correspondence, notes, employment documentation, and writings, reflects the sweep of Steck's interests and activities, and reveals how tightly interlaced were the activist and personal strands that ran through his life. This is especially apparent in his correspondence with other Abraham Lincoln Brigade veterans, many of whom were good friends, where debates about politics, issues and current events, planning for conferences and activities frequently occur in the same letters that share personal news. Notable here is correspondence with SCW veterans Homer Chase, Maury Colow, Moe Fishman, Benjamin Goldring, Herbert Kline, Ed Lending, Steve Nelson, Adolph (Buster) Ross, Randall Pete Smith, Irving Weissman, Milton Wolff and James Yates; a letter to Albert Prago on Jewish identity, Zionism, and the Middle East; and an exchange with George Watt about POUM, Orwell, and the Nazi-Soviet pact. There is ample documentation of Steck's involvement with the Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade (VALB), generated by the range of roles he assumed at the organization over the years. Materials include official correspondence, minutes and notes, and anniversary programs. Of note is an exchange between the Abraham Lincoln Brigades Archive, VALB, and the SCW Historical Society about stewardship of the veterans' archives.
Steck's writings not only demonstrate the breadth of his activities as a public figure, creating political theater and hosting scores of events and commemorative gatherings; they also convey his aspirations as a novelist, poet and screenwriter. His writings frequently demonstrate his commitment to presenting the history and lessons of the SCW; many writings appear only as fragments and drafts, with handwritten notes for speeches, scripts, lectures, and presentations.
Steck's association with Camp Unity and his directorship of Camp Calumet are evidenced here by oral histories by former Unity campers and staff, as well as original flyers, brochures, and retrospective publications. The file for Sophie Saroff's 80th birthday celebration contains a wealth of information about Saroff's life. An annual report of the House Un-American Activities Committee indicates its surveillance of Unity.
Original items from the SCW period include a program for a concert held by American Battalion members on board the R.M.S. Ausonia; an Agence Espagne statement (in French) calling for the U.S. to lift its embargo on Spain, titled "How Fascism Menaces the Americas"; a pamphlet, "Crime of Guernica"; two hand-compiled booklets; a League of American Writers and American Students Union flyer; and a poem by Muriel Rukeyser.
The series also offers a selection of Steck's official papers from World War II, as well as documents from his teaching career.
Series II. Prisoners of the Good Fight: Project Files (bulk 1936-1942; 1978-1986).
Steck's work with Carl Geiser on Prisoners of the Good Fight resulted in extensive research and correspondence, reflected in Series II. Copious handwritten notes and partial drafts describe prisoners and document communication with ex-prisoners and relatives. Also included are the original papers of former prisoners, as well as news articles from the SCW period, including those by New York Times reporter William Carney. Foreign Service communications update relatives regarding missing men and securing prisoners' release, while the U.S. Embassy reports on prison conditions. A number of transcripts record the recollections of ex-prisoners.
Of note in the biographical files (Subseries A) are letters documenting Walter Fairbanks Grant's father's attempts to find his son after he disappeared in Spain; Albert Ziegler's letters from Spain, including one explaining to his mother why he hadn't told her that he was going to fight; a manuscript by Henry Ben Megquier; a letter from the president of the New York State Economic Council reporting on his visit to Geiser in prison; a flattened bullet engraved by Steck; a deck of miniature playing cards; and an announcement for a "Three B's" party to Bring Bob [Steck] Back from prison. Sol Leiserowitz's file includes a letter he wrote to his sister from the battlefield and a letter from the State Department reporting that Leiserowitz could not be located. Other materials include a declassified FBI report (circa 1943) detailing Charles Keith's Communist affiliations; a hand-illustrated postcard from Leo Torgoff; a 1938 booklet, "Life & Death of an American Hero: The Story of Dave Doran," published by the Young Communist League; a letter from ex-prisoner Jimmy Moon listing prisoners smuggled out by Greek International Brigaders; and a Folkways pamphlet describing veteran Max Parker's recording of SCW songs.
Subseries B contains extensive correspondence between Steck and Carl Geiser, reflecting their close working relationship, with a daily exchange of letters during the height of the book's preparation. The relationship of VALB's Prisoner Historical Committee to the book project can be discerned. Also of note are Steck's research materials, evidence of fundraising efforts, and letters regarding publication. Other items include a 1937 pamphlet, "Italian Prisoners in Spain" (in Italian); and correspondence from the U.S. Embassy, Red Cross, and the Friends of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade documenting attempts to deliver money and essentials to prisoners. One issue of "Jaily News," represented here in photocopy, also exists in the original (please consult staff for access).
Arrangement
Series I arranged alphabetically. Series II arranged alphabetically within each subseries.
Organized into 2 series:
Missing Title
I. General Files
II. Prisoners of the Good Fight: Project Files
Related Material at the Tamiment Library/Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
ALBA collections at the Tamiment Library.
Carl Geiser Papers.
Separated Material
Photographs, audio tapes, maps and other non-print materials from the Robert Steck Collection have been transferred to the non-print section of the ALBA collection in the Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives.
Spain -- History -- Civil War, 1936-1939.; Spain -- History -- Civil War, 1936-1939 -- Personal narratives.; Spain -- History -- Civil War, 1936-1939 -- International brigades.; Correspondence.; Articles.; Speeches.; Personal papers.; Drafts (documents); Spain -- History -- Civil War, 1936-1939 -- Prisoners and prisons.; Camps -- New York (State) -- History -- 20th century.; San Pedro de Cardeña (Monastery: Castrillo del Val, Spain); Ebro River, Battle of the, Spain, 1938.; Research (document genres).; Jarama River Valley (Spain); Real Monasterio de San Pedro (Cardeña, Spain); Camps -- Massachusetts -- History -- 20th century.; Gandesa (Spain) |x History.; Spain |x History |y Civil War, 1936-1939 |x Concentration camps.; Brunete, Battle of, Brunete, Spain, 1937.; Spain -- History -- Civil War, 1936-1939 -- Participation, American; Spain -- History -- Civil War, 1936-1939 -- Veterans -- United States -- Correspondence.; Fishman, Mosess (Moe), 1916-2007; Parker, Max, 1912-1983.; Unity Camp (Wingdale, N.Y.); Veterans of the Abraham Lincoln Brigade; Yates, James, 1906-; Ziegler, Albert.; Camp Calumet (Wingdale, N.Y.); Committee for the Release of International Prisoners in Spain; Abraham Lincoln Brigade Archives; Goldring, Benjamin; Grant, Walter Fairbanks; Geiser, Carl; Megquier, Henry Ben; Kline, Herbert; Leiserowitz, Sol; Nelson, Steve, 1903-1993; Spain. Ejército Popular de la República. Brigada Internacional, XV; Moon, Jimmy; Chase, Homer; Carney, William; Doran, Dave, 1910-1938; Colow, Maury; Watt, George, 1913-1994; Torgoff, Leonard Sloan, 1916-1937; Weissman, Irving, 1905-; Steck, Robert; Saroff, Sophie, 1896-; Lending, Edward Isaac, 1912-2003; Prago, Albert; Ross, Adolph "Buster"; Smith, Randall, 1917-1989; Wolff, Milton.; Spain. Ejército Popular de la República. Abraham Lincoln Battalion
- Series I: General
  - Abortion Rights, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - ALBA-VALB-Spanish Civil War Historical Society Relationship, undated, Oct 1977-Nov 1985 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Alexander, Bill: International Brigade Association, Oct 1991 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Babi Yar, Sep 1987 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Barsky, Edward K., Feb 1967 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Berch, Victor, undated, Dec 1975-Jul 1986 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Bernardi, Herschel, undated, Jul 1971-Jul 1986 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Bessie, Alvah, Feb 1982-Jul 1985 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Bessie, Alvah: "The Good Fight" (unpublished anthology proposal), Mar 1985 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Block, Paul, Oct 1937 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Brandt, Joseph, Aug 1984 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Brandt, Joseph: "Fighting for Destruction of Fascism: WWII" (research paper), 1985 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Bruskin, Perry: "Telling It Like It Was" (documentary): Workers Laboratory Theater, undated, 1992-1995 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Cagney, James: Support for Loyalists in Spanish Civil War [??], undated (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Calendar page (Catalan): signed Paul Robeson, Charles Haldane (photocopy), 1938 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Camp Calumet: General, undated, 1960-1986 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Camp Calumet: Sale of, Dec 1954-Jan 1975 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Camp Kinderland, undated, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Camp Sharilawn Sherwood: Map, Nov 5 1954 (Flat-file-folder 7)
  - Camp Unity: 20th Anniversary Reunion Ball, Jan 1947 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Camp Unity: Accounts, 1945, 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Camp Unity: Brochures and Flyers, undated, 1959, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Camp Unity: Committee on Un-American Activities and Anti-CP Activities, undated, Jan 1947[?] (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Camp Unity: Correspondence (photocopies), 1946-1948 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Camp Unity: Correspondence, undated, Dec 1975-Feb 1994 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Camp Unity: Correspondence: Shapiro, Linn, undated, Jul 1979-Aug 1990 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - "Camp Unity and the Fight against White Chauvinism" (paper), Apr 1990 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Camp Unity: Freedom of Information Requests, undated, Apr 1979-Feb 1985 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Camp Unity: Jackman, Ken, on, Aug 1983 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Camp Unity: Lead Belly Project, undated, Jun 1991-Aug 1995 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Camp Unity: Matusow, Harvey, Sep 1981 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Camp Unity: Mendelson, Wilfred (Mendy), 1980-1987 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Camp Unity: Music, undated, 1964, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Camp Unity: Notes, undated (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Camp Unity: Singer, Ruth, Nov 1979 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Camp Unity: Theatrical Productions, 1940, 1948 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Camp Unity: Transcript of Gerson Interview, Mar 1983 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Camp Unity: Transcript of Letters from Campers, ca.1980 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Camp Unity: Transcript of Reuben Homer Interview, Aug 1983 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Camp Unity: Transcript of Robert Steck Interview, Mar 1979 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Camps: General, Jun 1986-Jul 1989 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Camps: Socialist Camps for Children, undated (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Carroll, Peter, Jan 1992 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - China: Dr. Norman Bethune International Peace Hospital, Jul 1985-Aug 1985 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - China: Steck trip to, undated (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - China: U.S.-China Peoples Friendship Association, Jun 1975-Apr 1976 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Cogswell, Theodore, undated (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Collins, Len, undated (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Colodny, Robert: on Vietnam, undated (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Colow, Maury, undated, Nov 1979-Mar 1985 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Conference: 50th Anniversary of the Spanish Civil War (Siena College), Jun 1986 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Conference: "First International Colloquium on the Spanish Civil War" (University of Barcelona), Apr 1979 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Conference: "Image of Spain in the Mass Media" (Rutgers University), Apr 1978 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Conference: "Malraux-Hemingway—Embattled Spain", undated, May 1937, Oct 1990 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Conference: The Spanish Civil War (Dartmouth College), Apr 1981 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Conference: The Spanish Civil War (University of Chicago), 1977 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Conference: "The Spanish Civil War and Its International Impact" (New School), Oct 1981-Dec 1981 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Conference: "The Spanish Civil War, A Retrospective Evening" (Center for Labor Research and Studies), Dec 1979 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Conference: Spanish Institute, Apr 1979 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Constantine, Ed, Dec 1986-Jan 1987 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Coordinadora Catalana d'Associaciones d'Ex-Combatants de la Republica, Jun 1987 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Correspondence: General, undated, Jan 1980-Feb 1996 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Correspondence: Get Well Wishes, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Correspondence: Greetings/Thank you's/Holiday Wishes, undated, Dec 1969-Jul 1994 (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Cowley, Malcolm: Support for Children in Spain, Sep 1937 (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Crank Letters, undated, Nov 1981 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Cuba, undated, Aug 1985 (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Cussen, Joseph, undated, Feb 1981-Aug 1981 (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Dallet, Joseph, Jr., undated (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Doyle, Joe, Jun 1983-Aug 1986 (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - El Salvador, Apr 1981-Oct 1981 (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Fishman, Moe, undated, Jun 1979-Aug 1994 (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - Funaroff, Sol: "Exile From a Future Time," Posthumous Poems (photocopy), 1943 (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - Geiser, Carl, undated, Nov 1992-Apr 1993 (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - Geiser, Carl: Correspondence, Feb 1990-Aug 1995 (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - Gerassi, John, undated, Nov 1979-Apr 1981 (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - Goff, Irving, Dec 1979 (Box 1, Folder 76)
  - Goldring, Benjamin, undated, Feb 1980-Oct 1986 (Box 1, Folder 77)
  - Goldstein, Ben (Butch), 1981 (Box 1, Folder 78)
  - Green Party, Jul 1996 (Box 1, Folder 79)
  - Hakam, Harry, Jan 1981 (Box 1, Folder 80)
  - Hamill, Pete, undated (Box 1, Folder 81)
  - Harriman, Manny, undated, May 1980 (Box 1, Folder 82)
  - Harris, Sydney, undated, Jul 1978-Dec 1983 (Box 1, Folder 83)
  - Hemingway, Ernest, undated, ca.1987 (Box 1, Folder 84)
  - Hiroshima, ca.1980 (Box 1, Folder 85)
  - Hudson, Hosea, undated, Jan 1980 (Box 1, Folder 86)
  - Hunter, Oscar, Nov 1979-Jul 1980 (Box 1, Folder 87)
  - Ibárruri, Dolores (La Pasionaria), undated, Jun 1983-Dec 1985 (Box 1, Folder 88)
  - Iceland, Ben, May 1982-Oct 1986 (Box 1, Folder 89)
  - Ickes, Harold, undated (Box 1, Folder 90)
  - "Identity and Politics in the Basque Country and Catalonia" (research paper), undated (Box 1, Folder 91)
  - Inter Theater, Jun 1986 (Box 1, Folder 92)
  - Irish Independence, undated (Box 1, Folder 93)
  - Japan Attacks China (article), 1937 (Box 1, Folder 94)
  - Keller, Fred, undated, Nov 1979-Dec 1993 (Box 1, Folder 95)
  - Kline, Herbert, undated, Jan 1980-Apr 1986 (Box 1, Folder 96)
  - Knox, Bernard, undated, Jul 1983 (Box 1, Folder 97)
  - Kozar, John (Topsy), undated (Box 1, Folder 98)
  - Lending, Edward, undated, Jul 1979-Sep 1998 (Box 1, Folder 99)
  - Markert, Clement, Anthony Demaio, and Robert Steck, Dec 1986 (Box 1, Folder 100)
  - Montell, Judith, May 1993 (Box 1, Folder 101)
  - Morel, Willan B.: Commendation from Sindicato de Tecnicos, Barcelona (photocopy), Nov 1938 (Box 1, Folder 102)
  - National Jewish Youth Conference, Aug 1956-Sep 1956 (Box 1, Folder 103)
  - Nelson, Steve, undated, Jul 1979-Apr 1986 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Nicaragua, undated, Oct 1984-May 1986 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Noble Horizons, 1989-1990 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Noll Gonzalez, Francisco, Nov 1938-Dec 1938 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - "Notes on Some International Problems": Azcárate, Manuel (article), May 1979 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Nuclear Disarmament, undated, Jun 1982-Oct 1992 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Nusser, Charles, undated, 1937, Jun 1985 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Obituaries and Memorials, undated, Dec 1971-Apr 1982 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Orwell, George, undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Ost, Milton, Nov 1981 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Peace Movement, undated, Nov 1981-Mar 1996 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Peekskill Riot, undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Political/Social Issues: Articles and Appeals, undated, Nov 1981-May 1986 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Postdoctoral Fellowships for Research in Spain, 1978-1979 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Prago, Albert, undated, Nov 1982-Jan 1993 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Prago, Albert: "40th Anniversary of Spanish Vets in Florence" ( Jewish Currents article), Feb 1977 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Prago, Albert: on Burnet Bolleten, undated (Box 2, Folder 17)